时间
Time.
空间
Space.
现实
Reality.
它们不仅仅是线性的
It's more than a linear path.
而是一个拥有无限可能的棱镜
It's a prism of endless possibility,
一个选择便能开辟出无数个现实
where a single choice can branch out into infinite realities,
创造出与你所知不同的平行世界
creating alternate worlds from the ones you know.
我是观察者
I am the Watcher.
我将带领你们穿越这些新现实
I am your guide through these vast new realities.
跟随我来  并思考这个问题
Follow me and ponder the question...
假如
第一季 第九集
季末大结局
"假如"呢
"What if?"
雷姆利亚星号
The Lemurian Star.
当海盗登上这艘船时  他们在发送最后的货物
They were sending their last payload when pirates took the ship.
-有多少海盗呢
-由巴作克领导的约二十名雇佣兵
-How many pirates?
-Twenty or so charmers led by Batroc.
法国特种部队革退他之前
Before French special forces showed him the door,
他完成过36次杀戮行动
he racked up 36 kill missions.
嗯  听起来更吸引你啊
Hmm. Sounds more like your type.
好吧  我有"盾"  你有"剑"
Fine. I've got the shield. You've got the sword.
是"刀"吧  这文字游戏真好玩
More like knives, but cute wordplay.
关掉引擎  找出人质  各位小心了
Kill the engines and find the hostages. Gentlemen, watch our six.
特击小队  听好队长的命令  整装出发
STRIKE Team, you heard the captain, gear up.
所以  星期六晚有什么计划吗
So, any plans for Saturday night?
没有  不要  够了
No, don't. Stop right there.
会计部的伯纳德有在打听你
Bernard in accounting was asking about you.
"会计部的伯纳德"这句之后都没好事发生
Nothing good has ever followed the phrase, "Bernard in accounting."
假如他的名字是史蒂夫呢
What if his name was Steve?
哎唷  寡妇啊  只在我们成为好兄弟时
Ouch! Just when we were becoming pals, Widow.
我以为你不仅只是一块盾牌
I thought you were more than just a shield.
我也是个相当不错的舞蹈家呢
I'm a pretty good dancer, too.
我太快了
I'm too fast.
喔  那很好
Oh! That was good.
-哇  -什么  你怕了吗
-Whoa! -What? Are you scared?
你看到了吗
Are you seeing that?
卡特队长  迷失在时间的战士  你已被选中了
Captain Carter, the soldier lost in time, you have been chosen.
哦  放马过来  放松吧  儿子
Oh, come on. Relax, son.
一千年后一切都将结束
It'll all be over in a thousand years or so.
嗯
Huh?
嘿
Hey.
留在这里  将这场战斗留给我们
Stay here. Leave this fight to us.
我知道了  是啊  和那穿斗篷的巨大男婴回来
I got it. Yeah. Hang back with the giant baby-man cape dude.
星爵特查拉  劫掠者的首领暨瓦坎达失落的王子
Star-Lord T'Challa, leader of the Ravagers and lost Prince of Wakanda,
你已被选中了
you have been chosen.
这些无限宝石
These Infinity Stones...
我已不做武器买卖  不是我的菜
I'm out of the weapons business, not my cake.
但我们如何让一套铁甲遍布全球  嗯
But how do we put a suit of armor around the world? Hmm?
遍布银河
Around the galaxy?
你不能告诉我没有另一个又大又坏
You can't tell me there's not another big, bad
潜伏在床底黑影中的怪物
lurking-in-the-shadows monster under the bed.
托尼
Tony!
葛摩?  斯卡星的幸存者和灭霸的毁灭者
Gamora, survivor of Sakaar and destroyer of Thanos...
还是一个将要踢你这个丑八怪的人
And one who's about to kick your moon-shaped, ugly mug.
不是你啊  史塔克  葛摩?你已被选中了
Not you, Stark. You, Gamora, have been chosen.
克尔芒戈必需按瓦坎达的法律以谋杀罪受审
Killmonger must be tried for murder under Wakandan law.
我们了结后  美国人可以逮捕他
The Americans can have him after we're finished.
埃里克·史蒂文斯  克尔芒戈
Erik Stevens, Killmonger,
托尼·斯塔克的前门徒和杀手
Tony Stark's former protege and killer,
你已被选中了
you have been chosen.
我们正准备去约会
We were about to go on a date!
那里会有花  我会点蜡烛
There were gonna be flowers, and I was gonna light candles,
我要去洗澡和造好发型
and I was gonna shower and do my hair.
没人会乱搞拉斯维加斯
Nobody messes with Vegas.
你吗  还有你
How about you? And you?
最后  托尔  奥丁的儿子  阿斯加德的王
Finally, Thor Odinson, Crown Prince of As...
还有你  还有你
And you. And you.
你已被选
You've been cho...
-你也是啊  -托尔  托尔
-Have at you, too. -Thor. Thor!
-还有你  还有你  -安静  冷静一下
-And you. And you. -Shh. Calm down.
托尔  奥丁的儿子  阿斯加德的王子
Thor Odinson, Crown Prince of Asgard...
你已被选中了
You've been chosen.
哦  我们在酒吧
Oh, we're in a pub.
我知道这个地方
I know this place.
这酒吧门面是我的主意
The pub facade was my idea.
我在你的传记中读过它  我希望你会喜欢
I read about it in your biography. I hope you like it.
这边  我  我  我可以喝杯啤酒
Over here. Me, me. Can I get a beer?
好
Yes!
-呃  你是谁  -我在哪里
-Uh, who are you? -Where am I?
你为什么带我们来这里  你要我们做什么
Why did you bring us here? What do you want with us?
都问得好
All good questions.
送我们回去  即刻
Send me back. Now.
-又是你  -老天鹅啊  用新花招吧  大佬
-It's you again. -Come on. Get a new trick, man.
你们已被选中
You have been chosen...
为了你们所认知的续命而执行
for a mission that is both highly dangerous and absolutely necessary
一项高度危险但绝对必要的任务
for the continuation of life as you know it.
最初  我在永恒中寻找一位真英雄
At first, I scoured eternity for one true hero.
然后我看到了更大的局面
Then I saw the bigger picture.
这任务需要一个团队
This mission requires a team.
只有这种技能和经验的完美结合才能致胜
The perfect combination of skills and experience that alone will triumph.
我开门见山吧
Let me get this straight.
你跨越银河系绑架了我们  所以我们可以什么
You kidnapped us from across the galaxy so we could, what?
拯救全宇宙吗
Save the universe?
嗯  不太正确
Mmm. Not exactly.
更复杂一点
Bit more complicated than that.
你们不只是拯救一个宇宙的最大希望
You aren't just our best hope to save one universe.
你们是拯救全部宇宙的最后希望
You are my last hope to save all of them.
你们是多元宇宙守护队
You are the Guardians of the Multiverse.
我知道这是什么  是洛基让你搞这个笑话
I know what this is. Loki put you up to this joke.
听好了  今天我没有时间恶搞
Listen, I do not have time for his pranks today.
不  我不会那样做
No, I wouldn't do that.
我的简小姐需要我  所以我要走了  好好享
My lady Jane needs me. So, I'll be going. Enjoy yourse...
我们加入了  介意告诉我们我们的对手是什么吗
We're in. Mind telling us what we're up against?
你的世界正在或快将被奥创攻击
Your worlds are either under attack or soon will be by Ultron,
奥创是一种由增强的合成体和无限宝石的力量升华
an artificial intelligence elevated to a cosmic being
而成为宇宙存在的人工智能
thanks to an enhanced synthetic body and the power of the Infinity Stones.
六块拥有近乎无限力量的宝石
Six stones of near unfathomable power.
每一块都控制着一个我们存在的必要本质
Each controlling an essential aspect of our existence.
而奥创已手握所有
And Ultron holds all of them.
我或者能帮忙  我从更坏的人手上偷过更多
I might be able to help with that. I've stolen more from worse.
认真的吗  你真的来自另一个星球
Seriously? You really are from another planet.
我们相信阻止奥创的唯一方法是将他的身体与宝石分开
We believe the only way to stop Ultron is to separate his body from the stones.
但这奥创可能隐藏在多元宇宙的任何地方吧
But this Ultron could be hiding anywhere in the Multiverse?
-是的  -在杀戮机械人军团的背后吗
-Yes. -Behind an army of killer robots?
-恐怕如此  -带着整套宝石吗
-Afraid so. -And armed with a full set of stones?
-她说中痛点  -我从没说过会很轻易
-She's got a point. -I never said it would be easy.
这是一个自杀式任务
This is a suicide mission.
嗯  对不起  是的
Um, excuse me, yeah.
有没有一个世界有跨维度的中餐料理送餐服务
Is there a universe of Chinese food that has alternate dimension delivery?
肚子打鼓愈来愈响
Tummy's getting rumbly.
你选了他们
You picked them.
好的  显然  第一步是找到他
Well, obviously the first step would be finding him.
好吧  我不是吹嘘自己
Well, I'm not one to brag,
但有人告诉我我擅长引起不必要的注意
but I've been told that I excel at attracting unwanted attention.
哦  那会派上用场的
Oh. That will come in handy.
我们回收宝石后  销毁它们
And after we recover the stones, we destroy them.
你会怎样摧毁那
How would you even go about destroying the...
哦  你在回答我的问题  对不起  谢谢你
Oh, you're answering my question. Sorry. Thank you.
无限破碎机
The Infinity Crusher,
设计来分解每块宝石成虚无
designed to disintegrate each stone into nothing.
是的  我选了他们
Yep. I picked them.
好吧  各位  你们都知道要做什么  知道计划
All right, everyone, you all know what to do. You know the plan.
夺得灵魂宝石  交给葛摩?
Get the Soul Stone and get it to Gamora.
我们守卫防线  她会释放破碎机
We'll hold the line. And then she'll unleash the Crusher.
加点运气  我们将回家吃饭
With some luck, we'll be home for dinner.
好吧  等等  放慢一点
Okay, wait. Slow down a little bit.
房间里有几个人不明白
There's a few people in the room that don't understand.
不是我  我明白  但他们  或得重覆一次
Not me. I get it. But for them, maybe repeat it.
嗯  你们准备就绪
Hmm. You're ready.
我的朋友们  好戏开场了  祝你们好运
It's showtime, my friends. Good luck.
这个地方安全吗
This place is safe?
显然  这里没有足够的智慧生物来吸引奥创
Apparently, there's not enough intelligent life here to attract Ultron.
直到我们决定
Until we decide to.
我问问  发生过什么事
Can I ask, what happened?
发生在你身上一样的事啊  老友
Same thing that happened to you. Love.
我猜你知道你所在宇宙的卡特队长吧
I take it you know the Captain Carter on your universe?
并不  美国队长
No. Captain America.
在我的宇宙里  是史蒂夫·罗杰斯接受了血清
In my universe, Steve Rogers received the serum.
现在  那将是一个风景
Now, that would be a sight to see.
你信任他吗
You trust him?
我相信所有人
I trust everyone.
快点  朋友们  今晚我们享受盛宴
Hasten, friends. Tonight we feast.
为了明天  我们战斗
For tomorrow, we fight.
本着这种精神  我提议干杯
In that spirit, I propose a toast.
-一些蜂蜜酒  太好了  -哦  我们在说话
-Some mead. Wonderful. -Ooh. Now we're talking.
一位聪明的法师告诉过我  面对死亡是计划的一部分
A wise sorcerer once told me that to face death is part of the plan.
面对死亡  是为了克服对虚无的空间
To face death is to conquer one's greatest fear of the unknown
对一切终结的未知的最大恐惧
of nothingless space, of the end of all ends.
毫无意义的虚无和无限向你敞开的
The senseless nothing and the vast opening of infinity to your...
我来  够了  医生
Let me. You've done enough, Doctor.
敬多元宇宙
To the Guardians of...
守护队
The Multiverse.
多元宇宙
The Multiverse!
毕竟  这个宇宙有生命
So there is life in this universe, after all.
一直等我们准备就绪
There goes waiting until we're ready.
我自辩一下  我警告过你
In my defense, I did warn you.
我擅长吸引不必要的注意力
I excel at attracting unwanted attention.
嗯嗯
Mmm-hmm.
好吧  这是一个不合规的咒语
All right, here comes a non-compliant spell.
是的  你可能会感觉到
Yeah, you might feel it.
哇
Whoo!
-哦  发生什么事  -这是一个保护咒语  不用谢
-Oh, what is going on? -It's a protection spell. You're welcome.
哇  太棒了  好戏上演  观察者
Wow! This is fantastic. Showtime. Watcher!
另一边见
See you on the flip side.
我知道如何应付这扫兴鬼
I know how to deal with this party pooper.
等等  托尔  计划啊
Wait! Thor, the plan.
拉斯维加斯万岁
Viva Las Vegas!
什么
What?
不能说我以前听过战斗的呐喊
Can't say I've heard that battle cry before.
一切都很简单
All too easy.
有趣
Interesting.
通常  你们这些人更容易被杀死
Usually, you people are much easier to kill.
老天鹅 连刮痕都没有
Blimey! Not even a scratch.
你的保护咒并非开玩笑
You weren't kidding about a protection spell.
你受到保护  但不会持续太久
You're protected, but it won't last long.
哇哦
Whoo!
-我们出手了  你确定吗  -当然不
-We're up. Are you sure about this? -Of course not.
我们来了  就是现在
Here we go. Now!
哈
Ha!
-你中招了  -滚
-Gotcha. -Get off!
你明白吗
Did you get it?
正如勇度所说  "永远别怀疑黏手指"
As Yondu says, "Never doubt sticky fingers."
冲啊  冲啊
Go! Go!
什么  你一直在隐匿什么啊
What? You've been hiding that the entire time?
好的  这一定很快活
Well, this has been delightful.
但是时候拿出一些我自己的玩具
But it's time for me to bring out some of my own toys.
我的宝石  你们偷了我灵魂宝石吗
My stone. You stole my Soul Stone?
要走了
Time to go.
-那会让他很忙  -哦
-That'll keep him busy. -Oh!
僵尸  好主意  我爱?尸
Zombies! Great idea. I love zombies.
不是他们  是僵尸带来的东西
It's not them. It's what came with the zombies.
喔
Oh...
把握时间  朋友们
Tick tock, boys.
哇
Whoo!
那真出乎意料
That was unexpected.
什么
What?
该死的该死的胡说八道
Blimey bloody bollocks!
你成功了
Oh, you made it.
-你准备好了  -宝石呢
-You ready? -The stone?
停手  等等  退下
No, wait. Stand down.
-她是娜塔莎·罗曼诺夫  -谁啊
-She's Natasha Romanoff. -Who?
是的  我也应该是这个星球上的最后一人
Yeah. I'm also supposed to be the last person on this planet.
我们来自另一个宇宙  各个宇宙
We're from another universe. Universes.
我们是来阻止奥创的
We're here to stop Ultron.
我可以做证
I can prove it.
你父亲是伊万  你的丈夫是阿列克谢
Your father is Ivan. Your da's Alexei.
你是我那个与我并肩作战到现在也信任的女人
And you're the one woman I trust to have my six, including now.
整个宇宙中你信任三个人
There are three people you trust in the universe,
我很庆幸能成为其中之一
and I count myself lucky enough to be one of them.
好吧  我们一定很亲密
Well, we must be close.
我相信"永远最好的朋友"
I believe the term is "BFF."
我相信你有属于我的东西
I believe that you have something that belongs to me.
娜塔莎
Natasha!
什
Wha...
我用一个念头就可以摧毁宇宙
I can destroy galaxies with a thought.
为什么你总是死不去
Why won't you die?
等等  什么
Wait. What?
用上你们所有的招数  别让他有机会思考
Give him all you've got. Don't give him a chance to think.
拉斯维加斯
Vegas!
你完了
You're done.
哇  呃
Whew! Uh...
-是吗  终于完了吗  -嗯
-Is that it? Is it over? -Hmm.
我们赢了吗  是吗  没那么难
We win? Yeah? Not so hard.
感觉还未完结
It doesn't feel over.
老实说  我很惊讶
I'm honestly surprised.
观察者没有警告过你们吗
Didn't the Watcher warn you?
每个宇宙都不同  每个宇宙都只有独一无二的部分
Every universe is different, each one just a fraction unique.
所以无限宝石是独一无二的
Thus the Infinity Stones are unique.
难怪啊
Of course.
破碎机是用来摧毁我宇宙上的无限宝石  不是他宇宙的
The Crusher was designed to destroy the stones on my world, not his.
振作准备
Brace yourselves.
你  是你啊
You. It's you.
如果我消灭你  你们全都会落败
If I destroy you, you all fall.
嘿  队长  我有个主意
Hey, Cap, I have an idea,
但我需要距离和明确的目标  你能做到吗
but I'll need distance and a clear target. Can you do that?
我有"盾牌"  你有"剑"
I've got the shield. You've got the sword.
更像是一支"箭"  箭尖是所有病毒之母
More like an arrow with the mother of all viruses in the tip,
但这文字游戏真好玩
but cute wordplay.
这是给你的  克林特
This one's for you, Clint.
这比我的人体要好多了
This is far nicer than my human body ever was.
谁在那里  谁说的
Who's there? Who said that?
这是一个引人入胜的变奏  对吧
This is a fascinating change of pace, yeah?
我已经很久没有双腿了
It has been a long time since I have had legs.
我想一直维持这个状态
I'd like to make this a permanent condition.
这个身体已被占用了
This body is occupied.
只是现在  但不会很久
For now, but not for long.
什么  你是谁  你有什么目的
What? Who are you? What is your objective?
曾几何时  它为了迎接九头蛇的统治
Once upon a time, it was to bring forth HYDRA's domination
但你终结了它
but you ended that.
所以现在  我想我要终结你
So now, I suppose my objective is to end you.
这是什么
What is this?
嘿  你没事吧
Hey, are you all right?
我很好  嗯嗯
I'm good. Mmm-hmm.
好的  那是  呃
Okay, that was, uh...
有人可以解释一下吗
Can someone explain, please?
我给他施打了病毒  很糟糕的一种
I gave him a virus. A nasty one.
堂哥  你在做什么呢
Cousin, what are you doing?
观察者欠我们的
The Watcher owes us this.
有了这些宝石  我们可以修复我们的宇宙  我们的生活
With these stones, we could fix our worlds, our lives.
特查拉  托尔
T'Challa, Thor,
你会放弃一件能拯救你们家园的物件吗
are you gonna turn down the one thing guaranteed to save your homes?
佩吉  你又可以和你的男朋友一起了
Peggy, you can be with your fella again.
斯特兰奇  你比谁都清楚  就是这样
Strange, you more than anyone know that this is it.
这是我们唯一的机会
This is our only chance.
把石头交出来  堂哥
Hand over the stones, cousin.
我不是你堂哥
I'm not your cousin.
我很抱歉要以这种方式结束
I'm sorry it has to end this way.
哦  不  不  不  恐怕那铁甲是属于我的
Oh, no, no, no. I am afraid that armor belongs to me.
是阿尼姆·左拉吗
Is that Arnim Zola?
九头蛇从未死亡  它只是变异了
HYDRA never died, it just mutated.
嗯  这就解释了肚上的面容
Well, that explains the stomach-face.
嗯
Huh?
我们从来没有打算赢
We were never meant to win.
我们来这里是为了将石头与身体分开
We were here to separate the stones from the body.
你预见过每一刻
You foresaw every moment
由无限粉碎机的失败  到克尔芒戈的背叛  以及我的
from the failed Infinity Crusher, to Killmonger's betrayal, and my...
你的牺牲
Your sacrifice.
"牺牲"
"Sacrifice"?
那意味着我有什么要失去的
That would imply I had something to lose.
需要有人照顾他们
Someone needs to attend to them.
如果那个口袋次元破裂  如果他们逃跑
If that pocket dimension cracks, if they escape...
我会观察
I'll watch.
除了时间  我什么都没有
I have nothing but time.
谢谢你  史蒂文斯
Thank you, Stephen.
嗯  此外  朋友有什么用呢
Mmm. And besides, what are friends for?
整个多元宇宙感谢你
The entire Multiverse owes you a debt of gratitude.
但是你们的世界永远不会知道这场胜利
But your worlds will never know this victory.
一旦你穿过那扇门
Once you walk through that door,
你们会回到离开的那一刻
you'll return to the exact moment you left.
是时候离开了  队长
It's time to go, Captain.
你宁愿回到另一个时间
You'd rather return to another time.
我不是已经赢得我的幸福结局吗
Haven't I earned my happy ending?
相信我  那个世界  那个时间
Trust me, that world, that time,
需要卡特队长
needs Captain Carter.
然后有一个宇宙
And then there was one.
我不会回去那里
I won't go back there.
我的宇宙已经
My world is...
消失了
gone.
你们赢了  但我输了
You won, but I lost.
-我不能干  -干预吗  是的  我知道
-I cannot in... -Interfere? Yeah, I know.
我们对你来说只是故事  我们不是真的
We're just stories to you. We're not real.
你看着我们战斗  胜利  失败
You watch us fight, win, lose.
告诉我  当奥创谋杀我的朋友并将我的世界夷为平地时
Tell me, did you make popcorn while Ultron murdered my friends
你有做爆谷吗
and burned my world to the ground?
对于我  你们不只是故事
You are more than that to me.
真的吗
Are we?
你们  你们的故事
You, your stories,
就是我的一切
they are everything to me.
那么修复我的世界
Then fix my world.
我不能啊  娜塔莎
I can't, Natasha.
我不会穿过那扇门
I'm not walking through that door.
好吧  无论如何  门更像是一个譬喻
Well, the door was more of a metaphor anyway.
哪里  我们在哪里
Where... Where are we?
在一个失去寡妇的宇宙中
On a world that lost their Widow.
一团糟
It's a mess.
谢谢你
Thank you.
嗯
Hmm.
你和你的复仇者后补们英勇奋战
You and your replacement Avengers fought valiantly,
但现在你是时候告诉我你所有的秘密了
but now I think it's time you told me all your secrets.
我被告知你已经死了
I was told you were dead.
彼此彼此
Same.
你不是我的娜塔莎
You're not my Natasha,
但我隐约知道你有她的灵魂
but something tells me you have her spirit.
就是这样  不是吗
That's it, isn't it?
所有的生物都在寻找一个属于自己的地方
All creatures searching for a place to belong.
一个家
To call home.
至于我  我是观察者
As for me, I am the Watcher.
多元宇宙  每一个宇宙  每一个故事都是我的家
The Multiverse, every single world, every story is my home,
我会保护它到底
and I will protect it to the end.
我太快了
I'm too fast.
别告诉我  他吸引到你吗
Don't tell me, he was your type?
哦  寡妇  我从来没有这么高兴能见到你
Oh, Widow, I've never been so happy to see you.
你是撞坏了脑袋  还是怎样
Did you hit your head or something?
撞了几次  真的
A few times, actually.
算了吧  这行动需要清醒的理智
Shake it off. You'll need all your marbles for this one.
我发现了海盗们的目的
I found what the pirates were after.
佩吉  你可能要振作准备
Peggy, you might wanna brace yourself.
娜塔  我可以向你保证
I can promise you, Nat,
这不会是我今天处理过最奇怪的事情
this won't be the strangest thing I've dealt with today.
继续吹
Famous last words.
九头蛇践踏者
The HYDRA Stomper?
是的  里面有人
Yeah, and there's someone inside.